A Guide to the Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial records, Counsel's Office, Series 10 FA358
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Robert R. Douglass, 1959-1972; 3; 65 Document Box(es)
  - Government - Municipal Police Training Council, 1965 (Box 19, Folder 191)
    Several memos recommending extension of number of hours of the basic police training course, and objecting to Sheriff Charles McClosky's continued chairmanship of the council; directory of police terminology.
  - Government - New England River Basin Commission, 1971 (Box 19, Folder 192)
    Commission proposal that New York City and Westchester County be included within its region to make comprehensive studies and recommendations regarding the Long Island Sound. NAR note, "Is this going to interfere with the bridge or power development?" (proposed Oyster Bay bridge across Long Island Sound).
  - Government - New York City - Budget-Fiscal, March 1972 (Box 19, Folder 193)
    New York State Division of the Budget analysis of New York City's executive expense budget, revenues, and expenditures.
  - Government - New York City - Budget, Fiscal, April 1972 (Box 20, Folder 194)
    Further analysis of New York City finances. Includes the city's school system, collective bargaining, New York State Comptroller Arthur Levit's audit reports, professors' compensation at City University of New York, state aid for City University of New York, and New York City's budget gap.
  - Government - New York City - Educational Construction Fund, 1966 (Box 20, Folder 195)
    Correspondence and draft legislation to create the New York City Educational Construction Fund, which would facilitate the financing of elementary and secondary school buildings primarily through combined occupancy projects.
  - Government - New York City - Fiscal, 1971 (Box 20, Folder 196)
    New York State Budget Department analysis of New York City's fiscal crisis, budgets, proposed tax packages, analysis of proposed solutions; summary of meeting with Deputy New York City Budget Director David Grossman; printed report, "A Tax Program for the City of New York," March 1971, no author; drafts of letter from NAR to New York City Mayor John Lindsay expressing disappointment at his failure to cut costs.
  - Government - New York City - Fiscal - Lindsay-NAR Fiscal Discussion, 1966 (Box 20, Folder 197)
    Two memos on fiscal legislative program for New York City agreed to at NAR-Lindsay breakfast meeting, December 1966.
  - Government - New York City - Fiscal - Lindsay Letter, April 19, 1971 (Box 20, Folder 198)
    Bound report outlining four proposed options for dealing with $500 million reduction in New York City budget caused by reduction in state aid to New York City, 168 pages.
  - Government - New York City - Fiscal - Fiscal Problems, 1967 (Box 20, Folder 199)
    Summaries of New York City's 1967-1968 fiscal situation.
  - Government - New York City - Jails-Legislation (Women's House of Detention), 1966 (Box 20, Folder 200)
    State assistance in relieving overcrowding at New York City jails, particularly at the House of Detention for Women.
  - Government - New York City - State Aid-Rat Extermination, 1964 (Box 20, Folder 201)
    Memos on the extent of state aid appropriate for New York City rat extermination program.
  - Government - New York City - Welfare Housing, 1971 (Box 20, Folder 202)
    Memos on New York State Division of Housing and Community Renewal's proposal to provide state assisted housing for families receiving public assistance, includes proposal.
  - Government - Planning Coordination (OPC), 1971 (Box 20, Folder 203)
    Published report, "New York State Development Plan," January 1971, 128 pages, issued by Office of Planning Coordination.
  - Government - Presidential Succession, 1966 (Box 21, Folder 204)
    Drafts of NAR's message to the New York State Legislature urging ratification of proposed Twenty-Fifth Amendment to the United States Constitution; copy of concurrent resolution of New York State Senate and Assembly ratifying proposed amendment.
  - Government - Regional Coordination Officers, 1966 (Box 21, Folder 205)
    One memo on proposed regional coordination office to help localities apply for federal aid programs.
  - Government - Urban Extension Service, 1966 (Box 21, Folder 206)
    Draft NAR message to Legislature and draft bill to establish Division of Urban Affairs.
  - Government - Washington Office (of New York State), 1970-1972 (Box 21, Folder 207)
    Correspondence, memos, and notes on the staffing, reorganization, mission, budget, and operations of the office; periodic status reports on pending federal legislation of interest to New York State.
  - Health - General, 1964-1965, 1970-1971 (Box 21, Folder 208)
    Correspondence on activities, duties, responsibilities, and authority of Health Department; State Employees Occupational Health Service; national health insurance; health insurance issues; health care costs; New York City Health and Hospital Corporation; health maintenance organizations; venereal disease control; hospital deficits; allowance to families caring for mental patients; recodification of public health laws; press releases on establishment of new county health departments; quarterly Department of Health reports; press release on clinical labs and blood banks; report on dental care in fluoridated (Newburgh) and nonfluoridated (Kingston) areas; correspondence and press releases on dangers of eating swordfish by pregnant women; Health Education and Welfare (HEW) closing of Public Health Service Hospital on Staten Island; comparison of President Nixon's and Senator Kennedy's national health insurance proposals; proposed New York State Family Planning Corporation; proposed changes in the Physically Handicapped Children's Program; act to prevent hospitals from requiring additional examinations for interns; lead poisoning programs; medical assistance reorganization plan; memo on shifting New York State hospital payment schedule; proposed revisions to Hill-Boston program for indigent hospital patients.
  - Health - Abortion, 1971-1972 (Box 21, Folder 209)
    Correspondence; legislation.
  - Health - Abortion Law Revision, 1965 (Box 21, Folder 210)
    New York Times editorial urging new definition; letter from Community Social Services.
  - Health - Assistance to Health Professions, 1966 (Box 21, Folder 211)
    Legislation for Training Grants; NAR press release.
  - Health - Blue Cross - Hospital Costs, 1965 (Box 21, Folder 212)
    News clips; correspondence; NAR press release.
  - Health - Cigarette Advertising, 1965 (Box 21, Folder 213)
    News clips; correspondence; memo on constitutionality of bill banning ads.
  - Health - Chiropractor Licensing, 1964 (Box 21, Folder 214)
    Press release; correspondence.
  - Health - Funeral Directors, 1964 (Box 21, Folder 215)
    Legislation to upgrade qualifications; NAR veto; correspondence.
  - Health - Ghetto Medicine Program, 1971 (Box 21, Folder 216)
    Correspondence
  - Health - Governor's Committee on Hospital Costs, 1964 (Box 21, Folder 217)
    Press releases; correspondence; draft contract between Committee and Hospital.
  - Health - Health and Mental Hygiene Facilities Improvement Corporation, 1968-1969 (Box 21, Folder 218)
    Press release; correspondence; legislation.
  - Health - Hospitals, General, 1969-1970 (Box 21, Folder 219)
    Press releases; correspondence on hospital jurisdiction.
  - Health - Hospitals and Nursing Home Loan Programs, 1970-1971 (Box 22, Folder 220)
    Legislation to ease grant of mortgages for construction; correspondence; memos.
  - Health - Hospital and Nursing Home Reimbursement Rates, 1971-1972 (Box 22, Folder 221)
    Memos and notes; position paper of Hospital Association; correspondence.
  - Health - Hospital Strike, Lawrence Hospital, Bronxville, 1964 (Box 22, Folder 222)
    Memos, news article; NAR press release.
  - Health - Legislative Report, Health Department, 1964 (Box 22, Folder 223)
  - Health - Legislative Program, Health, 1963-1965 (Box 22, Folder 224)
  - Health - Legislative Proposals, Health, 1963-1965 (Box 22, Folder 225)
  - Health - Legislation, Health, Comments, 1965 (Box 22, Folder 226)
  - Health - Legislative Proposals, 1964-1965 (Box 22, Folder 227)
    (Health Department) #1, #2 & #3.
  - Health - Legislative Proposals, 1964-1965 (Box 22, Folder 228)
    (Health Department) #4, #5, #9, #9R & #10.
  - Health - Legislative Proposals, 1964-1965 (Box 22, Folder 229)
    (Health Department) #12, #13 & #14.
  - Health - Legislative Proposals, 1964-1965 (Box 22, Folder 230)
    (Health Department) #18, #20 & #22
  - Health - Legislative Proposals, 1964-1965 (Box 22, Folder 231)
    (Health Department) #23, #24, #29 & #30
  - Health - Medical Complex, New York City, 1971 (Box 22, Folder 232)
  - Health - Pharmacists Professional Responsibilitiy Bill, 1964-1965 (Box 22, Folder 233)
  - Health - Pharmaceutical Society Bills, 1965 (Box 22, Folder 234)
  - Health - Roswell Park Hospital Bill, 1969, 1972 (Box 22, Folder 235)
  - Health - Staten Island Hospital Bill, 1971 (Box 22, Folder 236)
  - Health - Universal Health Insurance, 1967-1970 (Box 22, Folder 237)
    Correspondence; draft bills; Bills.
  - Health - X-ray Technicians, Board of Examiners Bill, 1964-1965 (Box 22, Folder 238)
  - Health - Hospital and Medical Care, 1959 (Box 23, Folder 239)
    Confidential Preliminary Report to Governor's Cabinet Committee by John S. Bourke, M.D., Executive Director, New York State Joint Hospital Survey and Planning Commission.
  - Health - Health Publications, 1963-1964 (Box 23, Folder 240)
  - Health - Environmental Conservation, 1970 (Box 23, Folder 241)
    Governor's Program Bill to create Department of Environmental Protection.
  - Health - Tocks Island Reservoir, 1972 (Box 23, Folder 242)
    Delaware River Basin Commission correspondence.
  - Health - Governor's Annual Message, 1965 (Box 23, Folder 243)
    Drafts of portions of message.
  - Health - Private Medical Schools, State Aid, 1971 (Box 23, Folder 244)
    Letter to Robert R. Douglass from Association of Medical Schools on deficits; Robert R. Douglass memo to NAR.
  - Horse Racing - Aqueduct Strike, 1967 (Box 23, Folder 245)
    Correspondence; agreement to introduce and recommend passage of legislation to increase percentage of pools retained by flat racing tracks.
  - Horse Racing - New York Racing Association (NYRA) Increased Purses, 1967 (Box 23, Folder 246)
    Correspondence; legislation and changes thereto.
  - Horse Racing - Off Track Betting (OTB) Task Force, 1972 (Box 23, Folder 247)
    Correspondence on appointments to task force.
  - Horse Racing - Harness Horse Racing Fund, 1965 (Box 23, Folder 248)
    Correspondence on setting aside funds for equine research and encouraging breeding harness horses.
  - Horse Racing - Finger Lakes Racing Association, 1965 (Box 23, Folder 249)
    Letter to Dr. Hurd from J. H. Murphy, Tax Commissioner.
  - Horse Racing - Off Track Betting, 1971 (Box 23, Folder 250)
    Correspondence; memos; reports.
  - Horse Racing - Off Track Betting, 1972 (Box 23, Folder 251)
    News articles; cost comparison to New York City Off Track Betting; Off Track Betting commission report to NAR; correspondence; Off Track Betting budget papers; proposed moratorium on Off Track Betting; Aqueduct strike.
  - Housing - State Rent Commission, September-October 1962 (Box 24, Folder 252)
    Personnel matters; correspondence on supplies; transcript of testimony of George Goldleaf, an indicted supplier of kitchen cabinets.
  - Housing - State Rent Commission, September-October 1962 (Box 24, Folder 253)
    Reports; memos; press releases.
  - Housing - State Rent Commission New York City, September-October 1962 (Box 24, Folder 254)
    Press releases on city-state rent control.
  - Housing - State Rent Commission New York City, July 1962-November 1963 (Box 24, Folder 255)
    Press releases and correspondence on city-state rent control.
  - Housing - State Rent Commission, February-August 1962 (Box 24, Folder 256)
    Corruption debate.
  - Housing - State Rent Commission, July-August 1962 (Box 24, Folder 257)
    Press releases; correspondence on city accusing state of corruption.
  - Housing - State Rent Commission, August-October 1962 (Box 24, Folder 258)
  - Housing - Albany Executive Apartments, Incorporated, 1965 (Box 25, Folder 259)
    First limited-profit housing project in Albany; description and brochure.
  - Housing - Housing Finance Agency (HFA) Loans to Nursing Homes and Hospitals, 1965-1966 (Box 25, Folder 260)
    Press releases; memos; bills.
  - Housing - Program, 1967 (Box 25, Folder 261)
    Memos; press release; correspondence; Steven Lefkowitz report.
  - Housing - Program, 1967 (Box 25, Folder 262)
    Draft of Governor's message; press release; Battery Park City brochure.
  - Housing - Program, 1969-1970 (Box 25, Folder 0262A)
    Correspondence; press releases; drafts of bills, memos, reports.
  - Housing, 1971 (Box 25, Folder 263)
    Community development; low rent; correspondence.
  - Housing, 1972 (Box 25, Folder 264)
    Housing Finance Agency; Mitchell-Lama; correspondence.
  - Housing - Urban Development Corporation (UDC) - Community Development, 1971 (Box 25, Folder 265)
    Correspondence; editorial.
  - Housing - Albany, 1971 (Box 25, Folder 266)
    Correspondence.
  - Housing - Floyd Bennett Field, 1971 (Box 25, Folder 267)
    Correspondence; development as housing and Gateway National Recreation area.
  - Housing - Floyd Bennett Field, 1972 (Box 25, Folder 268)
  - Housing - Battery Park City, 1967-1969 (Box 26, Folder 269)
    Correspondence, progress reports from C. J. Urstadt (Department of Housing and Community Renewal) to NAR; reports of meetings.
  - Housing - Battery Park City, 1971-1972 (Box 26, Folder 270)
    Correspondence; progress reports; reports of meetings.
  - Housing - Buffalo Stadium, 1970-1971 (Box 26, Folder 271)
    Correspondence; news reports.
  - Housing - Buffalo Stadium, 1971-1972 (Box 26, Folder 272)
    Urban Development Corporation (UDC) report; correspondence.
  - Housing - Community Development Article of New York State Constitution, 1970 (Box 26, Folder 273)
    Correspondence; proposals as to form; reports.
  - Housing - Community Development Article of New York State Constitution, January 1971 (Box 26, Folder 274)
    Reports; Draft of Legislation; correspondence.
  - Housing - Community Development Article of New York State Constitution, February 1971 (Box 26, Folder 275)
    Reports; meeting notes; proposals; correspondence.
  - Housing - Community Development Article of New York State Constitution, February-March 1971 (Box 27, Folder 276)
    Correspondence, memos, draft legislation.
  - Housing - Community Development Article of New York State Constitution, April-August 1971 (Box 27, Folder 277)
    Correspondence, legislation; proposals.
  - Housing - Urban Development Corporation (UDC), 1970-1972 (Box 27, Folder 278)
    Correspondence; Urban Development Corporation (UDC) Construction Contract; summaries of UDC projects; UDC bond issue (1971).
  - Housing - Urban Development Corporation (UDC) - Federal Section 236 Interest Subsidy Funds, 1971 (Box 27, Folder 279)
  - Housing - Congress of Racial Equality (CORE), 1971-1972 (Box 27, Folder 280)
    Correspondence on lottery.
  - Housing - Insurance Legislation - "Wrap-up Insurance", 1966 (Box 27, Folder 281)
    1965 veto; 1966 memos.
  - Housing - Corona Housing Matter, 1970-1971 (Box 27, Folder 282)
    Memos and news clipping - political - "Lomenzo Stay Out."
  - Insurance - Insurance Premium Taxes, 1970-1971 (Box 27, Folder 283)
    Memos on meeting on problem; Policy Statement by National Association of Insurance Commissioners; proposed legislation; correspondence.
  - Insurance - State Insurance Fund, 1971-1972 (Box 27, Folder 284)
    Memos on appointment of members.
  - Insurance - Universal Health Insurance, 1971 (Box 27, Folder 285)
    Task Force formation, memos.
  - Insurance - Insurance Department, 1964 (Box 27, Folder 286)
    Investigation of Retirement System - Robert R. Douglass memo.
  - Insurance - Insurance Department, 1964 (Box 27, Folder 287)
    Superintendent Stern's Policy concerns; letter to NAR.
  - Insurance - Interfiling - Unsorted Miscellaneous, 1964-1972 (Box 27, Folder 288)
    Various pieces of unsorted correspondence that were to be interfiled later by Robert R. Douglass's staff. More than twenty topics are included.
  - Insurance - Investigation Commission, State, 1965 (Box 27, Folder 289)
    News articles about charges by Mayor Wagner about an alleged bribe; memo regarding testimony before State Insurance Commission.
  - Judiciary - Family Court Act, 1961-1962 (Box 28, Folder 290)
    Statistical Report, 1961; Reports on replacement of Domestic Relations Court.
  - Judiciary - Criminal Justice, 1964-1965 (Box 28, Folder 291)
    Memo on Combating Crime; Special Report on Expenditures for Administration of Criminal Justice; correspondence on New York State Identification and Intelligence System (NYSIIS).
  - Judiciary - Pre-Trial Press Information, 1965 (Box 28, Folder 292)
    U.S. Attorney General speech "Free Press and Fair Trial."
  - Judiciary - Queens County District Attorney, 1965-1966 (Box 28, Folder 293)
    Appointment of Nat Hentel to fill vacancy; correspondence; political memos.
  - Judiciary - Full-time District Attorneys, 1963-1966 (Box 28, Folder 294)
    Bill to mandate full-time District Attorneys in counties with 100,000 population.
  - Judiciary - Court Appointments - Vacancies, 1966 and 1971 (Box 28, Folder 295)
    Correspondence, memos and resumes.
  - Judiciary - Judicial Conference Recommendations, 1966 (Box 28, Folder 296)
    Number of judges.
  - Judiciary - Federal, 1970 (Box 28, Folder 297)
    Biography of Lawrence W. Pierce.
  - Judiciary - Court Reform, 1971-1972 (Box 28, Folder 298)
    Memoranda on cost of unifying the Court System.
  - Judiciary - Temporary Commission on the State Court System, 1971 (Box 28, Folder 299)
    Proceedings; correspondence, goals.
  - Judiciary - Temporary Commission on the State Court System, January-February 1972 (Box 28, Folder 300)
    Proceedings; minutes; reports.
  - Judiciary - Temporary Commission on the State Court System, March 1972 (Box 29, Folder 301)
    Reports; minutes.
  - Judiciary - Temporary Commission on the State Court System, April-July 1972 (Box 29, Folder 302)
  - Judiciary - Criminal Justice, 1971-1972 (Box 29, Folder 303)
    Correspondence; bill to establish state-wide prosecutor.
  - Labor - Minimum Wage, 1964 (Box 29, Folder 304)
    Report of Governor Rockefeller's Committee on Minimum Wage.
  - Labor - Labor and Social Insurance, 1964-1965 (Box 29, Folder 305)
    Study; proposal for Governor's 1965 Annual Message to Legislature.
  - Labor - Fair Employment Clause, 1965 (Box 29, Folder 306)
    Clause in State contracts forbidding discrimination.
  - Labor - Worker's Compensation for Volunteers, 1966 (Box 29, Folder 307)
    Program bill to cover volunteers in State departments and agencies.
  - Labor - Minimum Wage, 1966 (Box 29, Folder 308)
    Memos on minimum wage ($1.50); draft legislation.
  - Labor - Job Development Authority, 1967 (Box 29, Folder 309)
    Bill to increase bonding authorization.
  - Labor - Labor Legislation Program, 1967 (Box 29, Folder 310)
    Unemployment Insurance; Worker's Compensation.
  - Labor - Hospital Strike, 1972 (Box 29, Folder 311)
    Memos; correspondence.
  - Labor - General, 1971-1972 (Box 29, Folder 312)
    Affirmative Action; work incentives; mine safety; manpower retraining.
  - Labor - Minimum Wage, 1971 (Box 29, Folder 313)
  - Labor - Telephone Strike, 1972 (Box 29, Folder 314)
    Correspondence, news clippings.
  - Labor - Strikes, 1972 (Box 30, Folder 315)
    Correction officers strike; memos on planning & deployment; Article 78 Injunction.
  - Office Safety and Health Administration (OSHA), 1971-1972 (Box 30, Folder 316)
    Correspondence, memos.
  - Labor - Striker Benefits, 1972 (Box 30, Folder 317)
    Editorials on unemployment payments to strikers; draft bill to amend Labor Law 592.
  - Law - Antitrust - Attorney General, 1960 (Box 30, Folder 318)
    Memo on GE price fixing plea in Philadelphia Federal Court.
  - Law - Domestic Relations - Adoption - Family Law, 1958-1961 (Box 30, Folder 319)
    Editorials; memos; correspondence.
  - Law - Matrimonial and Family Law, 1958 (Box 30, Folder 320)
    Transcript of Joint Legislative Committee Hearing, Buffalo July 8, 1958.
  - Law - Wiretapping - Berger v. New York, 1967 (Box 30, Folder 321)
    Copy of editorial; memo Robert R. Douglass to NAR.
  - Law - Election Law - Political Contributions, 1960; 1965-1966 (Box 30, Folder 322)
    Memos on corporate political contributions.
  - Law - Liuni Adoption, 1966 (Box 30, Folder 323)
    Memos on adoption by foster parents.
  - Law - Emergency Procedures, 1970 (Box 30, Folder 324)
    Memos on bomb threats to government buildings; strike by New York City uniformed services.
  - Law - Challenge Primary, 1965-1966 (Box 30, Folder 325)
    NAR veto of 1965 bill; 1966 bill.
  - Legislation - 1965 Legislative Proposals, 1964 (Box 31, Folder 326)
    Department and agency responses to request for 1965 bills.
  - Legislation - 1965 Legislative Proposals - Back-up, 1964 (Box 31, Folder 327)
    Back-up memos for proposals.
  - Legislation - Program - Election Law, 1963 (Box 31, Folder 328)
    Memo on legislation; bills for single annual primary election.
  - Legislation - Hospitals - Public Health Law Article 28, 1965 (Box 31, Folder 329)
    Governor's Committee on Hospital Costs report, April, 1965; comments on report; memos; bill for prepaid health insurance.
  - Legislation - Hospitals - Public Health Law Article 28, 1965 (Box 31, Folder 330)
    Memoranda; amendments to bill.
  - Legislation - Program Bills - Drafts, 1965 (Box 31, Folder 331)
    Miscellaneous bills.
  - Legislation - Friends of Animals, Incorporated, 1963-1964 (Box 31, Folder 332)
    Memo to Legislature on "False Deficit" of American Society for the Prevention of Cruelty of Animals (ASPCA).
  - Legislation - Organizations Legislative Proposals, 1967 (Box 32, Folder 333)
  - Legislation - Propositions and Amendments, 1967 (Box 32, Folder 334)
  - Legislation - Weekly Status Reports - Bills, 1967 (Box 32, Folder 335)
  - Legislation - Legislative Recommendations - Call, 1963-1965 (Box 32, Folder 336)
  - Legislation - Proposed Propositions and Amendments, 1965 (Box 32, Folder 337)
  - Legislation - Joint Legislative Committee Hearings, 1965 (Box 32, Folder 338)
  - Legislation - Legislative Programs, 1966 (Box 32, Folder 339)
    Statewide organizations.
  - Legislation - Status Sheets (Legislation), 1966 (Box 33, Folder 340)
  - Legislation - Constitutional Amendments, 1966 (Box 33, Folder 341)
  - Legislation, 1965-1966 (Box 33, Folder 342)
    NAR correspondence to those who wrote concerning legislation.
  - Legislation - Program Suggestions for 1967, 1966 (Box 33, Folder 343)
  - Legislation - Aging - Building Design, 1966 (Box 33, Folder 344)
  - Legislation - Agricultural Land Preservation, 1967 (Box 33, Folder 345)
  - Legislation - Air Pollution Control - Interstate Commission, 1967 (Box 33, Folder 346)
  - Legislation - Building Conservation and Fire Prevention Code, 1967 (Box 33, Folder 347)
  - Legislation - Commerce - Puerto Rico Problem, 1966 (Box 33, Folder 348)
  - Legislation - Commerce - Post Viet Nam Transition, 1966 (Box 33, Folder 349)
  - Legislation - Commerce - Oceanography, 1966 (Box 33, Folder 350)
  - Legislation - Community Development Agency, 1967 (Box 33, Folder 351)
  - Legislation - Compulsory Health Insurance, 1967 (Box 33, Folder 352)
  - Legislation - Conservation Department, 1967 (Box 33, Folder 353)
  - Legislation - Conservation - Public Access, 1966 (Box 33, Folder 354)